Guide to the Everett and Evelyn Ortner papers and photographs ARC.306
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 6: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation general files, circa 1880-2008; 43750; 22.45 Linear Feet in eleven manuscript boxes, five flat boxes, two small boxes, two film canisters, and one oversize folder
  - Film on Brooklyn: Restoration of Bedford Stuyvesant (VHS tape), circa 1990s; 49538 (Box 78, Cassette 1)
    This film has been digitized and is available on Brooklyn Historical Society's Internet Archive account. "https://archive.org/details/arc.306_box78_restorationofbedfordstuyvesant">View the video here.
  - Film on Brooklyn: Downtown Brooklyn (VHS tape), circa 1990s (Box 78, Cassette 1)
    This film has been digitized and is available on Brooklyn Historical Society's Internet Archive account. "https://archive.org/details/arc.306_box78_downtownbrooklyn">View the video here.
  - Film on Brooklyn: Rebirth of Atlantic Avenue (VHS tape), circa 1990s (Box 78, Cassette 1)
    This film has been digitized and is available on Brooklyn Historical Society's Internet Archive account. "https://archive.org/details/arc.306_box78_rebirthofatlanticavenue">View the video here.
  - Film on Brooklyn: Partnership in Prospect Heights (VHS tape), circa 1990s (Box 78, Cassette 1)
    This film has been digitized and is available on Brooklyn Historical Society's Internet Archive account. "https://archive.org/details/arc.306_box78_partnershipinprospectheights">View the video here.
  - Film on Brownstone Brooklyn: The Brownstones of Brooklyn (VHS tape), circa 1990s; 49539 (Box 78, Cassette 2)
    This film has been digitized and is available on Brooklyn Historical Society's Internet Archive account. "https://archive.org/details/arc.306_box78_brownstonesofbrooklyn">View the video here.
  - Film on Brownstone Brooklyn: Cinderella of Berkeley Place (VHS tape), circa 1990s (Box 78, Cassette 2)
    This film has been digitized and is available on Brooklyn Historical Society's Internet Archive account. "https://archive.org/details/arc.306_box78_cinderellaofberkeleyplace">View the video here.
  - Film on Brownstone Brooklyn: My, My Brooklyn (VHS tape), circa 1990s (Box 78, Cassette 2)
    This film has been digitized and is available on Brooklyn Historical Society's Internet Archive account. "https://archive.org/details/arc.306_box78_mymybrooklyn">View the video here.
  - Film on Brownstone Brooklyn: Brooklyn, USA -- the Rebirth of an American City (VHS tape), circa 1990s (Box 78, Cassette 2)
    This film has been digitized and is available on Brooklyn Historical Society's Internet Archive account. "https://archive.org/details/arc.306_box78_brooklynusa">View the video here.
  - The Battle of Long Island (VHS tape), circa 1990s; 49540 (Box 78, Cassette 3)
  - Pirnie (VHS tape), circa 1990s; 49541 (Box 78, Cassette 4)
    In a case labeled "The Brownstones of Brooklyn" -- it is unclear whether the case relates to the tape
  - Flatbush: Architecture and Urban Development from Dutch Settlement to Commercial Strip, 1990; 43863 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - You Gotta Have Park! poster (Prospect Park), 1990; 49451 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Episcopal Church of St. Luke and St. Matthew - Sesquicentennial celebration, 1991; 43864 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Great New York State Wine and Food Festival poster (Fulton Ferry Landing), 1992; 49446 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - "Living in the City" by EHO typescript, 1992; 43865 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Civil War - Brooklyn, 1993; 43866 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Park Slope: Northern Exposure - 34th Annual House Tour poster, 1993; 49450 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Brooklyn Celebrates - 30th Anniversary of the Landmarks Preservation Law poster, 1995; 49436 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
  - Green-Wood Cemetery, 1995; 43867 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - BAM fundraising correspondence, 1996; 43868 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - "The Glory that was Brooklyn Beer" by EHO typescript and research, 1996; 43869 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    Includes Brooklyn Brewery ephemera
  - EHO lectures and other Brownstone events, 1996-2005; 43870 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - New York City Landmarks Preservation Commission - Rowhouse Manual, circa 2000; 43871 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - "Volunteers At Work" - Preserving America's Historic Sites - Preservation Volunteers (VHS tapes - 2 copies), 2002; 49543 (Box 78, Cassette 6-7)
  - "Volunteers At Work" - Preserving America's Historic Sites - Preservation Volunteers (VHS tapes - PAL format), 2002; 49544 (Box 78, Cassette 8)
  - WNYC "Brooklyn Brownstones" program audio cassettes (two copies), 2002; 44099 (Box 52, Folder -)
    Profile of EHO
  - WNYC "Brooklyn Brownstones" program print outs, 2002; 44101 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Charles Lockwood correspondence, 2003; 43872 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Leffert's House (VHS tape), 2003; 49545 (Box 78, Cassette 9)
  - Brownstones, 2003-2010; 43873 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    Includes Develop Don't Destroy Brooklyn, Preservation Volunteers, Brownstoner bibliography, advertisement for EHO talk "Brownstones and the Brownstone Age," Brownstone Revival Coalition press releases, and Park Slope walking tour
  - Preservation Volunteers - Reports and photographs, 2004; 43874 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - "Don't Tell Mayor Brooklyn Bloomberg About the Brownstone Bargain: Low, Low Real Estate Taxes" by EHO, 2005; 43875 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Robert Furman - Before Brooklyn and After sample chapters, 2006; 43876 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - "Brownstone violation" clipping, 2007; 49411 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Open House New York, 2007; 43877 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Park Slope Civic Council - Civic News, 2008; 43878 (Box 47, Folder 10)
- Series 7: Brownstone Revival Comittee records, 1967-2008; 43638
  The series contains files relating to the Brownstone Revival Committee (BRC) (later Brownstone Revival Coalition), dating from 1967 to 2008. It includes organizational records, lecture and workshop files, copies of the Brownstone calendar, and issues of the organization's publication, The Brownstoner.
  Additional files related to the BRC can be found in Series 3: Everett and Evelyn Ortner personal papers, Series 5: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation lectures, Series 6: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation general files, Series 8: Back to the City Conference, Series 9: Brownstones and Historic Preservation clippings, and Series 10: Brownstone correspondence.
  Sub-series 7.1: Brownstone Revival Committee administrative records
  Sub-series 7.2: Brownstone Revival Committee lectures, seminars, and workshops
  Sub-series 7.3: The Brownstoner
  Sub-series 7.4: Brownstone calendars and photographs
  Sub-series 7.5: H. Dickson McKenna files
  - Sub-series 7.1: Brownstone Revival Committee administrative records, 1967-2008; 43651; 5.85 Linear Feet in two manuscript boxes, four folders, and two oversize folder
    The sub-series contains administrative records of the Brownstone Revival Committee (BRC) (later the Brownstone Revival Coalition), dating from 1967 to 2008. They include Board of Directors files, correspondence, reports, financial records, photographs, home-buyer's guides, one scrapbook, and ephemera.
    The BRC organized the first Back to the City conference in 1974, and some files related to that conference are found in this sub-series.
    - BRC Historic, 1967-2004; 43652 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      Includes 1979-1986 board meeting minutes
    - Home-Buyer's Guide to New York City Brownstone Neighborhoods, 1969; 43653 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - BRC - General I, 1969-1975; 43654 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - BRC - General II, 1968-1974; 43655 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - BRC - General III, 1970-1986; 43656 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - BRC "Gems", 1970s-1998; 43657 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      Includes Park Slope walking tour, Gowanus typescript by John Muir, lists of recommended professionals and craftpersons, and other documents
    - BRC vs. IRS, 1970-1971; 43658 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Brownstone Surveys, 1971-2002; 43659 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Back to the City tour, 1974; 43660 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - BRC - Publicity, 1974-1976; 43661 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      Includes Back to the City
    - BRC bank, mortgages, and bankers, 1975-1976; 43662 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - BRC board meetings, 1977-1983; 43663 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      Includes financial records
    - BRC Guide to New York City's Fine Old Neighborhoods (fourth edition), 1979; 43665 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Brownstone Revival Committee scrapbook, 1979-1980; 49427 (Box 77, Folder -)
    - Brownstone Revival Committee and Brownstone Fairs, 1980-1987; 43666 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Includes photograph of Brooklyn Borough President Sebastian Leone and Brooklyn Union Gas Company President Eugene Luntey with Brownstone billboard
    - Reverse Mortgages, 1982-1994; 43667 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Includes Ortners' reverse mortgage application for 272 Berkeley Place and issues of the Brownstoner (Spring and Winter 1989, Spring 1990, and Fall 1993)
    - Brownstone Revival Coalition of New York, 1982-2007; 43668 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Brooklyn Brownstone Fair posters, 1986; 49400 (Box 75, Folder -)
    - BRC brochure layout, 1986; 49399 (Box 75, Folder -)
    - BRC correspondence, 1986-2000; 43669 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Brownstoner Ad appeal/rates, 1986-2004; 43670 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Brownstone Awards, 1989-1993; 43671 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - BRC membership forms, circa 1990s; 43672 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Grants, 1990-1996; 43673 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - BRC miscellaneous, 1995-1998; 43674 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - BRC Board of Directors, 1996-1997; 43675 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - BRC brochure, 1996-2001; 43676 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - BRC bills, 1996-2003; 43677 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - BRC board meetings and mailing lists, 2008; 43678 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series 7.2: Brownstone Revival Committee lectures, seminars, and workshops, 1970-2004; 43639; 0.65 Linear Feet in twelve folders
    The sub-series contains files relating the lectures, workshops, and seminars produced by the Brownstone Revival Comittee (later the Brownstone Revival Coalition), dating from 1970 to 2004. It includes correspondence, flyers, programs, lecture notes, slide lists, and photographs.
    Additional lectures delivered by EHO, some of which may have been produced by the Brownstone Revival Committee, can be found in Sub-series 3.1: Personal papers, memorabilia, and photographs, Sub-series 3.3: Publicity, and Series 5: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation lectures. Slides were used by EHO in his lectures can be found in Sub-series 4.3: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation slides.
    - BRC lectures, 1970-1974; 43640 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - BRC lecture notes and slide lists (2 folders), 1970s-2004; 43641 (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
    - BRC lecture, "A New Skyline for Brownstone Brooklyn?", 1990-2002; 43642 (Box 26, Folder 1, digital files)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Donated on one 3.5 inch floppy disk, containing two digital files in .dat and .doc formats. Digital ID arc_306_media_001.
      Access to digital materials is available onsite at the Othmer Library. Requests to access digital materials must be made at least 2 days in advance by emailing library@brooklynhistory.org.
    - BRC seminars, 1996; 43643 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - BRC fall seminars, 1998; 43644 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - BRC workshops, 1980-2001; 43645 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - BRC workshop, 1990; 43646 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - BRC workshop, 1991; 43647 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - BRC workshop, 1992; 43648 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - BRC workshop, 1994; 43649 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - BRC workshop, 2001; 43650 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Sub-series 7.3: The Brownstoner, 1968-2005; 43410; 0.25 Linear Feet in three folders
    The sub-series contains issues of The Brownstoner, the newsletter for the Brownstone Revival Committee (later the Brownstone Revival Coalition), dating from 1968 to 2005. The newsletter includes articles on historic home renovation, state and local legislation concerning historic homes and home buying, finances (mortgages, insurance, etc.), cultural events, street beautification, walking tours and lectures, landmarking, and gentrification.
    - The Brownstoner, 1968-1970; 43581 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - The Brownstoner, 1971-1972; 43582 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - The Brownstoner, 1973-1974; 43583 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - The Brownstoner, 1975-1976; 43584 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - The Brownstoner, 1977-1978; 43585 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - The Brownstoner, 1979-1980; 43586 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - The Brownstoner, 1981-1982; 43587 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - The Brownstoner, 1983-1985; 43588 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - The Brownstoner, 1986-1987; 43589 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - The Brownstoner, 1988-1989; 43590 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - The Brownstoner, 1990-1992; 43591 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - The Brownstoner, 1993-1997; 43592 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - The Brownstoner, 1998-2005; 43593 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Sub-series 7.4: Brownstone calendars and photographs, 1985-2006; 43411; 0.65 Linear Feet in thirteen folders
    The sub-series is subdivided into calendars and photographs. Each section is arranged chronologically.
    The sub-series consists of calendars produced by the Brownstone Revival Committee (later the Brownstone Revival Coalition) and copy photographs (prints, negatives, and contact sheets) that were featured in the calendars, dating from 1985 to 2006. The calendars include images of 19th century New York (primarily Manhattan) and advertisements for businesses related to brownstones and historic home renovation. The photographs portion of the sub-series includes some images that were not used in the calendars. The sub-series does not include calendars for the following years: 1986, 1987, and 2003.
    Additional copy slides of images used in the calendar can be found in Sub-series 4.3: Brooklyn and Historic Preservation slides.
    - Brownstone calendars, 1985, 1988-1997; 43594 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Brownstone calendars, 1998-2002, 2004-2006; 43595 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Brownstone calendar - Prints and negatives, circa 1980s-1990s; 43596 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Includes photograph of EGO and Clem Labine
    - Brownstone calendar - Negatives and contact sheets, 1988; 43597 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Brownstone calendar - Prints and negatives, 1990; 43598 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Brownstone calendar - Prints, 1991; 43599 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Brownstone calendar - Pix not used, 1991; 43600 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Brownstone calendar - Negatives, 1991-1992; 43601 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Brownstone calendar - Prints and negatives, 1994-1995; 43602 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Brownstone calendar - Prints and negatives, 1998-1999; 43603 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Brownstone calendar - Prints, negatives, and captions, 2002; 43604 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Brownstone calendar - Negatives, 2003; 43605 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Brownstone calendar - Prints, 2000s; 43606 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Sub-series 7.5: H. Dickson McKenna files, 1972-1994; 43679; 1.8 Linear Feet in three folders and one oversize folder
    The sub-series contains the Brownstone Revival Committee (BRC) and Back to the City Conference records of H. Dickson McKenna, dating from 1972 to 1994. McKenna was an organizer and speaker at the first Back to the City Conference in 1974, and served as the Treasurer and board member of the BRC in the 1980s and 1990s.
    - H. Dickson McKenna's Back to the City file, 1972-1974; 43680 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - H. Dickson McKenna's BRC board files, 1981-1982; 43681 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - H. Dickson McKenna's BRC board files, 1985-1994; 43682 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - H. Dickson McKenn'as BRC financial records, 1984-1992; 44110 (Box 72, Folder -)
- Series 8: Back to the City Conference records, 1973-1992; 43716
  The series contains records relating to the Back to the City Conference (BTTC), dating from 1973 to 1992. It includes the records of the organization (Board of Directors files) and files relating to individual conferences.
  Additional BTTC files can be found in Series 7: Brownstone Revival Comittee, Series 9: Brownstones and Historic Preservation clippings, and Series 10: Brownstone correspondence.
  The series in divided into two sub-series:
  Sub-series 8.1: Back to the City Conference administrative records
  Sub-series 8.2: Back to the City Conference - Annual conferences
  - Sub-series 8.1: Back to the City Conference administrative records, 1973-1992; 43683; 5.1 Linear Feet in four manuscript boxes, one small box, and one oversize folder
    The sub-series contains administrative records of the Back to the City Conference (BTTC), dating from 1973 to 1992. It includes Board of Directors files, financial records, correspondence, newsletters, and ephemera. It also includes files on conferences and other events where EHO represented BTTC.
    - Back to the City seal, 1970s; 44094 (Box 69, Item -)
    - BRC foundation appeal, 1970s; 43684 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - BTTC stationery, 1970s; 43685 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1973-1975; 43687 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - BTTC proceedings matters, 1974-1975; 43688 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - BTTC leaflet, 1975; 43689 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation and Rider 8, 1975; 43690 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - BTTC corporate matters and contracts, 1975-1976; 43691 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Documents / Articles, 1975-1976; 43692 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - BTTC Board of Directors and Advisory Board correspondence, 1975-1978; 43693 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - BTTC Board of Directors meetings, 1975-1983; 43694 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - BTTC Board of Directors minutes and by-laws, 1975-1980; 43695 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1975-1979; 43696 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - BTTC contacts, 1975-1980; 43697 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - BTTC and BRC correspondence, 1975-1986; 43698 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence to/from preservation organizations, 1975-1986; 43699 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - BTTC check book and finances, 1975-1992; 43700 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Administrative Code J-51, 1976; 43701 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - International Downtown Executives Association Mid-Year Conference - Little Rock, Arkansas, 1976; 43702 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      EHO led BTTC panel
    - BTTC News Reports and literature, 1976-1980; 43703 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - BTTC general files, 1976-1985 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - American Institute of Architects - Preservation of Historic Resources conference - Colorado Springs, Colorado, 1977; 43704 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      EHO spoke at conference
    - Richard Crissman correspondence, 1977; 43705 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - City Living '78 poster, 1978; 49445 (Cabinet Flat file A, Drawer 1)
    - Old House Workshop - Buffalo, New York, 1978; 43706 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      EHO presented for Back to the City
    - Housing for the Elderly conference - Detroit, Michigan, 1978; 43707 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      EHO delivered keynote address
    - Preservation Action, 1978-1981; 43708 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Columbia proposal, 1979; 43709 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - BTTC Board of Directors, 1979-1986; 43710 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - EHO Westover School talk, 1980; 43711 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Urban Visitors Network, 1981; 43712 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - BTTC financial records, 1981-1982; 43713 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - BTTC miscellaneous, 1982; 43714 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - BTTC Board of Directors meetings, 1982-1983 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - The Townscape Institute, 1983; 43715 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Sub-series 8.2: Back to the City Conference - Annual conferences, 1974-1986; 43717; 2 Linear Feet in four manuscript boxes and two folders
    Arranged chronologically by the date of each conference. The first file in the sub-series contains participant lists from each conference.
    The sub-series contains files on the annual Back to the City Conferences, dating from 1974 to 1986. The files document the organizing and logistics of each conference, and include correspondence, programs, brochures, posters, financial records, press releases, photographs, and ephemera relating to the cities in which the conferences were hosted.
    - BTTC Conference participant lists, 1974-1984; 43718 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Back to the City Conference - New York, New York, 1974; 43719 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Back to the City Conference - New York, New York press kit, 1974; 43720 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Back to the City Conference - St. Paul, Minnesota, 1975; 43721 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Back to the City Conference - Washington D.C., 1976; 43722 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Back to the City Conference - San Antonio, Texas, 1977; 43723 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Back to the City Conference - Hartford, Connecticut (2 folders), 1978; 43724 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
      Includes Connecticut Governor Ella Grasso and Hartford Mayor George A. Athanson
    - Back to the City Conference - Louisville, Kentucky (2 folders), 1979; 43725 (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
      Includes Louisville Mayor William B. Stansbury
    - Back to the City Conference - Wilmington, Delaware, 1980; 43726 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Back to the City Conference - Milwaukee, Wisconsin (2 folders), 1981; 43729 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
    - Back to the City Conference - Milwaukee, Wisconsin - EHO speech, 1981 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Back to the City Conference - Jim Thorpe, Pennsylvania / Mauch Chunk (2 folders), 1982; 43727 (Box 34, Folder 3-4)
    - Back to the City Conference - Brooklyn, New York, 1983; 43728 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Back to the City Conference - Brooklyn, New York, 1983 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Back to the City Conference - Miami Beach, Florida, 1984; 43730 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Back to the City Conference - Cleveland, Ohio, 1985; 43732 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Back to the City Conference - Cleveland, Ohio (2 folders), 1985 (Box 79, Folder 5-6)
    - Back to the City Conference - Fort Wayne, Indiana, 1986 (Box 79, Folder 7)
- Series 9: Brownstones and Historic Preservation clippings, 1966-1985; 43731; 2.3 Linear Feet in three manuscript boxes and one oversize folder
  The series contains clippings relating to brownstones and the historic preservation movement, including the Brownstone Revival Committee (BRC), Back to the City Conference (BTTC), and the Brooklyn Union Gas Company's Cinderella project, dating from 1966 to 1985.
  - Brownstone clippings and ephemera (4 folders), 1966-1982; 43733 (Box 35, Folder 2-5)
    Includes BRC, BTTC, Brooklyn Union Gas Company - Cinderella projects, and Brooklyn Museum
  - EHO stuff - Book (BTTC clippings), 1968-1984; 43734 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Historic Preservation articles, 1970s; 43735 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - BTTC / BRC clippings (1-3 of 4 folders), 1974-1979; 43736 (Box 36, Folder 2-4)
    Includes some correspondence and ephemera
  - BTTC / BRC clippings (4 of 4), 1974-1979; 44124 (Box 73, Folder -)
  - Housing and BTTC clippings, 1975-1982; 43737 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Housing clippings, 1979; 43738 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Housing clippings (3 folders), 1979-1981; 43739 (Box 37, Folder 1-3)
  - BTTC / BRC clippings, 1984-1985; 43740 (Box 37, Folder 4)
- Series 10: Brownstone correspondence, 1965-2005; 43521; 0.4 Linear Feet in five folders
  The series consists of correspondence relating to brownstones and the urban historic preservation movement, especially in the Park Slope neigborhood of Brooklyn, dating from 1965 to 2005. It includes several organizations, such as the Park Slope Betterment Committee, the Brownstone Revival Committee, and the Back to the City Conference. It also includes several local politicians, such as U.S. Congressman Fred Richmond, U.S. Congresswoman Yvonne B. Burke, U.S. Congressman Leo C. Zefferetti, Mayor Edward I. Koch, and Borough President Howard Golden.